welcome back to the channel this week we
are going to look at
a classic flavor we've actually
specifically got haagen-dazs cookies and
cream now i haven't had this for years
i'm not going to say how many years but
a long long time ago my brother and i
used to convince our mum to take us down
to blockbusters in our local town and
i'd go straight for the freezer where
all the haagen-dazs were stored
and you know fluttery eyebrows mama mum
please i'm gonna flutter my eyebrows i
don't know why i said flutter eyebrows
but look you can
it's just like an idiot anyway let's see
if this stuff is still as good as i
remember
massive over exposure
[Music]
it kind of tastes the same
it's kind of lost some of its magic
a little bit it it actually this tastes
just like vanilla ice cream
it tastes like vanilla ice cream
with very few pieces of
cookie in it which is a little bit
disappointing i remember it being
really heavily speckled with cookies and
a really creamier
a really creamier with a really creamy
kind of taste as well as texture i mean
texture is great haagen-dazs ice cream
is incredibly good so
you can't really fault them for that but
i might just rather than copy this
exactly i might just try and switch it
up a little bit and try and recreate the
flavor that i remember as a kid so
originally this ice cream was called
oreo ice cream but they had to change
the name many years ago for ip reasons
everyone knows what it is some people
make it with the cream inside the oreo
some people don't some people say that
it's just vanilla ice cream with the
paths of the oreos who knows everyone
does it differently let's try and make
this as it should be
as this is a basic vanilla ice cream
according to haagen-dazs that's what
we're gonna start with so put your milk
your sugar
your egg yolks and your skim milk powder
into the pan
get it all nicely mixed together and
then bring it up to temperature you're
gonna have to mix this a fair few times
because you've got those egg yolks in
there bring it up to about 75 to 85
degrees c
at that stage you can add in the oreo
cream center now i've used 50 grams of
this in here which is an entire pack of
double stuffed oreos once it's all
melted in take it off the heat and put
in a container
at that stage add in your cream and then
finally add your vanilla extract and put
it in the fridge to chill completely
once your ice cream is completely
chilled put it in your ice cream machine
to churn
now whilst it's churning you want to
take your
leftover
cookies from your pack of double stuffed
oreos and chop them up nice and small
take some aside and powder them though
i've used two to three halves of cookies
get that powder really fine and put
everything aside for later
once your ice cream reaches soft serve
consistency you can start adding in your
oreo powder and your oreo pieces if
you've got a nice strong machine if not
you might have to stir these in after
when it's ready you can start loading up
your tub and put it in the freezer
the haagen-dazs
goes pretty hard it's like hardened
dials now um it does say on the back
interestingly enough
15 minutes to wait now i'm sure it used
to be less than 15 minutes so
someone's changed something in there
likely
sugar
but
we're gonna get some scooped up and see
how close we actually got
[Music]
there we go they both scooped quite
similarly
that's quite difficult to say instantly
there's a color difference the
haagen-dazs is actually quite white in
color ours is
darker we put the powder obviously a lot
i don't even see the powder in the
haagen-dazs version so they obviously
don't put it in they just put in now
they just put in the little flecks of
cookie
obviously we've put the powder in ours
as well
and we've put the cookie pieces in i've
tried to make ours approximately the
same fat content etc and sugar content
as the haagen-dazs one
it's quite difficult to establish what
that is now because they've reduced the
information they put on their website
and on the back of the tubs
but knowing how
haagen-dazs creates ice cream was
somewhere in a 13 to 14
fat
range somewhere in the 17 to 18 sugar
range so that's what we've kind of
established and accomplished here let's
see what they taste like shall
we now
they taste identical they taste
identical they're both vanilla ice cream
with bits of oreo whether you put the
oreo dust in it or not it doesn't do
anything to the flavor it's just an
aesthetic thing
if you're trying to
achieve haagen-dazs cookies and cream
this recipe is going to get you pretty
damn close
if you make your cookies and cream
different
let us know how you do it i know
different countries do it different
different companies do it differently
and different individuals make it
differently so it's open to
interpretation as most things are in
life so with all that said and done
we hope you enjoyed this video don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
you